Guide to the George Pierce Baker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
George Pierce Baker papers
1910-1949
YCAL MSS 385
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.1
(5 boxes)
The George Pierce Baker Papers contain scripts from a scenario workshop that he taught at Yale and student papers from other courses.
Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Early acquistion information unknown. Transferred from Yale School of Drama, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
George Pierce Baker (1866-1935)
George Pierce Baker was an American drama educator. He graduated from Harvard University in 1887 and from 1888 to 1924 was a faculty member in the English Department. While at Harvard, he played a key role in starting the Harvard Theatre Collection at Harvard University Library; he created the Harvard Dramatic Club; and he founded Workshop 47 to provide a forum for the performance of plays developed for his English 47 class. Baker was unable to convince Harvard to offer a degree in playwrighting and in 1925 he accepted a position at Yale University. At Yale, he helped found the Yale School of Drama and remained there until his retirement in 1933.
Scope and Contents
The George Pierce Baker Papers contain scripts from a scenario workshop that he taught at Yale and student papers from other courses.
American drama; Theater scripts; Educators; Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935; Yale School of Drama; Yale University -- Faculty
- Theater scenario workshop scripts, 1947
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Barber, Philip. "W. Charcoal" (Box 1)
  - Bates, Esther. "Freedom For All Forever" (Box 1)
  - Bates, Esther. "For Your Freedom and Ours: The Case of Poland" (Box 1)
  - Buck, Gertrude. "Mother-Love" (Box 1)
  - Butterfield, Walton. "The Next Step On" (Box 1)
  - Froome Jr., John Redhead. "Dayspring" (Box 1)
  - Fuller, Lois C. "A Right to Live" (Box 1)
  - George, Roy. "The Hearth" (Box 1)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann. "The House of Magic" (Box 1)
  - Halman, Doris F. "Will-O'-The-Wisp" (Box 1)
  - Hawkridge, Winifred. "The Florist Shop, Alias the Price of Orchids" (Box 1)
  - Hinkley, Eleanor Holmes. "A Flitch of Bacon" (Box 1)
  - Ketchum, Arthur. "The Other One" (Box 1)
  - Kimball, Astrid. "Court Favour" (Box 1)
  - Lindall, Norman C. "Cooks and Cardinals" (Box 1)
  - MacDonald, Anna Sprague. "Yvon the Darling" (Box 1)
  - McFadden, Elizabeth Apthorp. "Christmas Chimes" (Box 2)
  - Osborne, Hubert. "The Readjustment" (Box 2)
  - Osborne, Hubert. "The Good Men Do" (Box 2)
  - Pillot, Eugene. "The Simms-Vane Incident" (Box 2)
  - Prosser, William L. "Free Speech" (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Violet B. "Home Sweet Home" (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Violet B. Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Smith, Rita Creighton. "The Rescue" (Box 2)
  - Sullivan, Elizabeth Higgins. "The Strongest Man" (Box 2)
  - Taylor, L.M. "Cockrow" (Box 2)
  - Winslow, Helen Sterling. "The Wonder Worker" (Box 2)
  - "La Boca De Pepita," sheet music (Box 1)
- Student papers, 1910-1916, 1949
  Arranged alphabetically by paper title.
  - List of student paper titles and authors and notes on unidentified scripts, 1949 (Box 3)
  - "The Actor-Manager of the Eighteenth Century and His Effect on the Drama" (Box 3)
  - "American Drama - 1900-1913" (Box 3)
  - "The London..." (Box 3)
  - "The Battle of Alcazar" (Box 3)
  - "Ben Johnson's Catiline" (Box 3)
  - "Bussy d'Ambois" (Box 3)
  - "Catiline, His Conspiracy" (Box 3)
  - "Continuation of the first part of the thesis ending with 'The wise woman of" Hodgson' (Box 3)
  - "Cyril Tourneur" (Box 3)
  - "The Devil's Charter" (Box 3)
  - "The Dramatic Craftsmanship of Mr Bernard Shaw" (Box 3)
  - "Dramatic Devices of Marston" (Box 3)
  - "Eleanor Hoffmann - English 39" (Box 3)
  - "The Fair Maid of Exchange" (Box 3)
  - "'Falstaff' H. G. files" (Box 3)
  - "Heaven Helps Him" (Box 3)
  - "His Womenfolk" (Box 3)
  - "A History of American Revivals of Elizabethan and Jacobean Plays" (Box 3)
  - "'Jud von Venedig' - translation" (Box 3)
  - "The Last Four Plays of Shakespeare" (Box 3)
  - "The Last Incarnation of Faust" (Box 3)
  - "Laporte, Cloyd. The Late Work of Shakespeare" (Box 3)
  - "The Only Girl in Sight" (Box 3)
  - "The Plays of George Wilkins" (Box 3)
  - "Poland: books consulted" (Box 3)
  - "The Princess and the Pedlar" (Box 3)
  - "The Principal Characters of the Three Last Plays of Shakespeare" (Box 3)
  - "'Ragusa"'- a trilogy by Ivo Vujnovic" (Box 3)
  - "The Realism of Thomas Middleton" (Box 3)
  - "'The Rebound' - Comedy by Thomas Robinson" (Box 3)
  - "Reested Stock" (Box 4)
  - "The Relation of the Elizabethan Satire to the Satirical Comedies of the Period" (Box 4)
  - "The Revesby Sword Play" (Box 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Arranged and produced by George Pierce Baker.
  - "Second part of the trilogy 'Dusk'" (Box 4)
  - "Shirley and the Comedy of Manners" (Box 4)
  - "Shirley's Comedies of Manners", 2 (Box 4)
  - "Something New about Thomas Heywood" (Box 4)
  - "The Sources, Date and Authorship of 'The famous Victories of Henry V' " (Box 4)
  - "A Strange Land" (Box 4)
  - "Synge and His Plays" (Box 5)
  - "Technique of the Drama of Thomas Middleton: Bibliography" (Box 5)
  - "Third part of the trilogy 'Nightfall on the terrace'" (Box 5)
  - "University Drama of Oxford to 1642" (Box 5)
  - "The Waves of Torre" (Box 5)
  - "The Wedding" (Box 5)